Drew Kerrigan

Summary

Java Node / JS

Solidity

Experienced and high performing software engineering generalist, driven by curiosity and the desire to write quality code used by millions of people. Interested in solving hard problems, learning new technologies, and open-source software.

Elastic

Containers

Messaging Queues

571.296.7081

Professional Skills

drew@kerrigan.io

| Languages | Specialties | Technologies |
|--------------------------------|---|------------------------------|
| Elixir | Software Development | Kubernetes |
| Erlang / OTP | System Architecture | Mesos |
| Golang | Infrastructure Automation | Kafka |
| Python | Performance Benchmarking | Nifi |
| ■ C/C++ | Networking / Load Balancing | Minio |
| Java | Data Modeling | Ethereum |

Distributed Systems

API Design

Data Pipelines

Verica Inc. APRIL 2021 - PRESENT

PRINCIPAL SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Implemented an Elixir-based SaaS (using the PETAL stack) which runs security audits using the open-source Prowler AWS security scanning tool on the backend. Lead the complete rearchitecture of Verica's Continuous Verification Platform (CVP) product, re-writing it in Golang from the previous Python implementation. Implemented a scalable Kafka load-testing and feature verification framework, as well as several Kafka-based verifications to ensure clusters are performing as expected at runtime.

Utilized: Elixir, Golang, Python, Terraform, AWS, Kafka, Kubernetes

Notable Projects: Elixir-Based SaaS: Prowler Pro, Continuous Verification Platform (Closed-Source)

Institutional Shareholder Services MAY 2018 - APRIL 2021

LEAD SOFTWARE ENGINEER - INNOVATION LAB

Lead a small team responsible for architecting and deploying an Apache Mesos based data platform for container orchestration, machine learning pipelines, data services, and GitOps. Wrote automation software, including CI/CD pipelines, Ansible, and Mesos frameworks to deploy and manage Kubernetes clusters, databases, and several internal applications. Open source projects include a Apache Nifi processor for the Stanford NLP library: Blog Post: Augmenting Data in Pipelines with NLP, and an Apache Mesos framework to orchestrate the deployment of Ethereum blockchain clusters: Blog Post: Ethereum on DC/OS.

Utilized: Erlang/OTP, Golang, Python, Java, Solidity, Node + ReactJS, Kubernetes, Mesos, DC/OS, Riak

Notable Projects: Mesos Framework: dcos-ethereum, Mesos Framework: dcos-besu, Nifi **Stanford Core NLP Processor**

Previous Employment

Drew Kerrigan

571.296.7081

drew@kerrigan.io

Mesosphere August 2016 - MAY 2018

SOFTWARE ENGINEER - SYSTEMS AND NETWORKING, SOLUTIONS ARCHITECT

Worked on the engineering team with a focus on networking and service discovery components of the DC/OS (Datacenter Operating System) product. Software defined networking / infrastructure make up the majority of the networking team's responsibilities. Projects include Marathon-LB, Mesos-DNS, Navstar, and Spartan for service discovery, DNS propagation and management. Lead architect and developer Edge-LB, a distributed layer7 load balancer built on DC/OS and Apache Mesos as a framework. Worked on-site and remotely with DC/OS customers performing a variety of professional services including system architecture design, software development, distributed systems and Mesos consulting. Delivered services to DC/OS / Mesos users with broad backgrounds in the financial, gaming, telecom, and media / entertainment industries. Employed knowledge and experience with containers, data pipelines, messaging queues, network architecture, and system administration.

Utilized: Erlang/OTP, Golang, Python, Java, C, Lua, Mesos, DC/OS

Notable Projects: Edge-LB (Closed-Source), Mesos-DNS, Navstar, DC/OS-adminrouter

Basho Technologies MAY 2012 - AUGUST 2016

PROFESSIONAL SERVICES ARCHITECT

Delivered professional services and architecture consulting with a focus on large scale system architecture and backend development. Supported full product lifecycles for Basho products, community driven projects, and client uses-cases / applications. Became very familiar and proficient with a variety of technology stacks. Client facing software/devops consulting from architecture to deployment and everything in between. Also contributor to open source software projects as well as many projects internal to Basho. Focused on distributed systems and building data solutions for difficult problems.

Diving into new technologies and platforms and quickly becoming proficient in fast changing environments according to customer needs and project requirements.

Utilized: Elixir, Erlang/OTP, Golang, Mesos, Ruby, Node.js, Python, Java, Hadoop, Riak, Riak CS

Notable Projects: <u>Riak Mesos Framework</u>, <u>Riak Explorer</u>, <u>Riak Elixir Client</u>, <u>Riango</u>, <u>Nagios</u> <u>HTTP JSON</u>

Stella & Dot MARCH 2011 - MAY 2012

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Lockerz, Inc. NOVEMBER 2009 - MARCH 2011

LEAD SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Swift JUNE 2007 - NOVEMBER 2009

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Education

West Virginia University 2003 - 2007

COLLEGE OF ENGINEERING

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science